The Papers of Georg and Max Bredig
Science History Institute
- Series II: Max Bredig Papers, II
  - Series II: Sub-Series I: Max Bredig Correspondence File
    - Kleiderkammer der Judischen Gemeinde - Correspondence/Acknowledgement of Gift
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 29
    - Helfman, Harry - Correspondence regarding Affidavit of Support for Victor and Marianne Homburger (13 items)
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 14
    - Bredig, Rosa - Correspondence to her son (14 items)
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 33
    - Judisches Wohlfahrts und Jugendamt - Correspondence/Acknowledgement of Gift
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 27
    - Gordon, William H. - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 8
    - Bredig, Max - Correspondence to Hermann Wismer - Draft
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 23
    - Bredig, Max - Correspondence to Ernst Hauser regarding Wolfgang Ostwald's ties to the Nazi Party - Drafts with printed article
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 30
    - Fajans, Kazimierz - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 3
    - Urey, Harold & Bernard J. Brent - (Max Bredig) - Correspondence regarding fund for K.F. Bonhoeffer (15 items)
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 17
    - Creighton, H. Jermain - Correspondence regarding Affidavit of Support for Georg Bredig (12 items)
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 36
    - Lambie, Margaret - Correspondence/Telegrams regarding Fritz Hochwald
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 31
    - Fajans, Kazimierz - Correspondence regarding death of Georg Bredig (11 items)
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 4
    - Homburger, Marianne - Correspondence to Max et al. regarding getting herself and family out of Europe. Sent from Karlsruhe as well as Camp de Gurs (82 items)
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 19
    - Manhattan Civilian Defense Volunteer Office - Correspondence and acknowledgement of Max's volunteer role as a stretcher bearer for the Red Cross
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 33
    - Homburger, Paul and Marianne - Correspondence to Charlotte and Dr. Rosenberg
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 20
    - Reis, Alfred - (Max Bredig) - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 6
    - Reis, Alfred - (Max Bredig) - Correspondence from Nazi Occupied France
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 5
    - Bredig, Georg - Correspondence/Postcard
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 10
    - Homburger, Marianne - Correspondence/Postcards sent prior to deportation from Baden (20 items)
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 18
    - Fuchs, Bill - Correspondence to Max Bredig together with letters from Victor & Marianne Homburger to Bill Fuchs (13 items)
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 7
    - Neumann - (Max Bredig) - Correspondence from Camp de Gurs
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 39
    - Hochwald, Fritz - Correspondence from inside Miranda Del Ebro Detention Camp (18 items)
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 16
    - Homburger, Viktor and Marianne - Correspondence (36 items)
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 21
    - Society for the Protection of Science and Learning - (Max Bredig and Paul Homburger) - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 14
    - Bredig, Georg - Correspondence (17 items)
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 9
    - Pohl, Robert Wichard - (Max Bredig) - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 40
    - Fajans, Kazimierz - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 2
    - Homburger, Walter - Correspondence from the step-son of Marianne while in England as part of the Kindertransport
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 22
    - Haber, Fritz - Correspondence/Letter of recommendation on behalf of Max Bredig to K.H. Meyer (13 items)
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 11
    - Bredig, Max - Correspondence/Appeals for Aid for Fritz Hochwald (104 items)
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 26
    - Civilian Defense Corps of the City of New York - Correspondence regarding invitation to become a Gas Reconnaissance Officer
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 34
    - Adler, E.M. - Legal correspondence regarding the Homburger family
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 1
  - Series II, Sub-Series II: Max Bredig Subject File
    This sub-series contains manuscript items (not including correspondence) that were collected and saved by Max Bredig. Of note are items related to Max's philanthropic activities which primarily focused on providing relief for Jewish Refugees. Items in the sub-series are arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Scientific Drawings on Scrap Papers, undated
      Graphic Materials box 10 folder 32
    - Notes on scrap paper (53 items), undated
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 26
    - Newspaper Clipping regarding Jewish Refuges and Transportation to the United States (13 items)
      Text box 10 folder 24
    - Employment History and Reference Letters (12 items)
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 11
    - Medical Certificate and Bills
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 21
    - International Education Board - Application for Fellowship
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 19
    - Allgemeine Treuhand-Stelle fur die Judische Auswanderung (General Trustee's Office for Jewish Emigration)
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 1
    - Christmas Cards - Unmarked, undated
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 7
    - Funeral Arrangements for Georg Bredig (27 items)
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 13
    - Army-Navy Production Award - Presentation Booklet for Ward to the Bridgeville Division of the Vanadium Corporation of America
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 2
    - Newspaper Clipping regarding enemy aliens in the United States (28 items)
      Text box 10 folder 25
    - Scholarship Application - Includes drafts
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 31
    - Walden, Paul - Clipping, photograph of Walden at Breslau Congress
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 35
    - Deutschen Mitgleider der Jewish Agency und Das Prasidium des Keren Hajessod - Organizational Literature
      Text box 10 folder 9
    - Tennessee Valley Authority - Employment opportunity (49 items)
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 34
    - Jewish Aid Societies - Contribution receipts (63 items)
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 28
    - Intelligence Report on the Kaiser Wilhelm Institute (Photostat)
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 18
    - Einstein, Albert - Article from New York Times Magazine
      Text box 10 folder 10
    - Scientific Notes and Sketches regarding solutions of metals in Liquid Ammonia
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 33
    - Invoices and Receipts
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 20
    - Association of Oak Ridge Engineers and Scientists - Newsletters and Minutes (62 items)
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 4
    - Hospital Charges preceding the death of Georg Bredig
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 15
    - Newspaper Clipping regarding Dutch Atomic Energy
      Text box 10 folder 22
    - Sailing Schedules and Passenger Fees, Europe to the United States (31 items)
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 30
    - Curriculum Vitae
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 8
    - German Income Tax Act (58 items)
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 14
    - Association of New York Scientists - Newsletters (30 items)
      Text box 10 folder 3
    - Newspaper Clipping regarding Carl Neuberg, Jewish Refugees and Canadian Science
      Text box 10 folder 23
    - "Referat in Chemische Colloquium" - Notes by Max Bredig
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 29
    - Bollen-Zeitung - High School Graduation Newspaper
      Text box 10 folder 6
    - Philanthropic Activities - Organizational Literature and Appeals (53 items)
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 27
    - Identification Papers - German Passport, German ID Cards, Photographs, and Passport Holder
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 16
    - Association of Scientists for Atomic Education - Application and Meeting Minutes
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 5
    - Financial Documents (139 items)
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 12
    - Immigration Papers (59 items)
      Mixed Materials box 10 folder 17
- Series III: Publications, III
  Series III contains all published items found in the collection including books, journals, and offprints.
  - Series III, Sub-Series I: Offprints
    Georg Bredig collected the offprints of his scientific writings and bound them together into six volumes, arranged by subject. A bibliography of each volume's content was typed and included at the front of each volume. Volume I also contains an overview of the collected works. Each offprint was assigned a number by Bredig which corresponds to the bibliographies and appear on loose Bredig offprints in the collection. Georg Bredig also collected the dissertations completed in his laboratory and under his supervision. He bound these offprints into four volumes, arranged alphabetically by author.
    - G. Bredig u. Mitarbeiter. V. No. 124-155, Elektrochemie.
      Books box 19 volume 5
    - Scwartz, W. and H. Lang - Offprint
      Text box 15 folder 8
    - Ghosh, J.C. - Offprints
      Text box 13 folder 3
    - Brode, Johannes - Offprint
      Text box 12 folder 4
    - Grimm, H.G. - Offprints (23 items)
      Text box 13 folder 7
    - Bredig, Georg - Offprints, no. 67-81 (17 items)
      Text box 11 folder 15
    - Bortini, Fr. - Offprint
      Text box 11 folder 8
    - Carter, Frederick E. - Offprint
      Text box 12 folder 8
    - Goldschmidt, V.M. - Offprints, (2 of 2)
      Text box 13 folder 6
    - Bodenstein, M. - Offprint
      Text box 11 folder 4
    - Lachs, Hilary - Offprint
      Text box 14 folder 13
    - Bredig, Georg - Offprints, no. 120-135 (12 items)
      Text box 11 folder 18
    - Findlay, Alex - Offprint
      Text box 12 folder 15
    - Jannasch, P. and Henry F. Harwood - Offprint
      Text box 14 folder 4
    - Fromherz, Hans - Offprints
      Text box 13 folder 2
    - Cohen, Ernst - Offprints (12 items)
      Text box 12 folder 9
    - Walton, James Henri - Offprint
      Text box 16 folder 6
    - Hild, K. and G. Tromel - Offprint
      Text box 13 folder 12
    - Knapp, Wilhelm - Offprint
      Text box 14 folder 6
    - Elod, E. and H. Nedelmann - Offprint
      Text box 12 folder 13
    - Kroepelin, H. and E. Vogel - Offprint
      Text box 14 folder 9
    - Bredig, Georg - Offprints, no. 1-15 (17 items)
      Text box 11 folder 11
    - Reis, Alfred - Offprints
      Text box 15 folder 2
    - G. Bredig u. Mitarbeiter. IV. No. 90-123, Allgemeine, Anorgan. u. Organ., Katalyse.
      Books box 18 volume 4
    - Fraenkel, W. - Offprints
      Text box 13 folder 1
    - Snethlage, H.C.S. - Offprints
      Text box 16 folder 1
    - Dessauer, Friedrich - Offprint
      Text box 12 folder 11
    - Bloch, R., et al. - Offprint
      Text box 11 folder 3
    - Wolf, Erich - Offprint
      Text box 16 folder 10
    - Bredig, Georg - Offprints, no. 141-154 (11 items)
      Text box 12 folder 1
    - Tromel, G. - Offprints
      Text box 16 folder 5
    - Disertationen aus G. Bredig's Laboratorium. Band IV. P-Z.
      Books box 20 volume 4
    - Bruni, Giuseppe - Offprint
      Text box 12 folder 6
    - Kab, Georg - Offprint
      Text box 14 folder 5
    - G. Bredig u. Mitarbeiter. III. No. 61-89, Asymmetrie, Diazoessigester.
      Books box 18 volume 3
    - Rindell, Arthur - Offprints
      Text box 15 folder 4
    - Kruss, Gerhard - Offprints
      Text box 14 folder 10
    - Mark, Herman - Offprints
      Text box 14 folder 15
    - Beutler, H. and E. Rabinowitsch - Offprint
      Text box 11 folder 2
    - Pohl, R. - Offprints
      Text box 15 folder 1
    - Wust, J. & H. Reindel - Offprint
      Text box 16 folder 12
    - Spear, Ellwood Barker - Offprint
      Text box 16 folder 3
    - Holeman, P. and H. Goldschmidt - Offprint
      Text box 13 folder 14
    - Bredig, Georg - Offprints, no. 156-185 (18 items)
      Text box 12 folder 2
    - Bredig, Georg - Offprints, no. 83-95
      Text box 11 folder 16
    - Maschke, Alfred - Offprint
      Text box 14 folder 16
    - Reis, Emil - Offprints
      Text box 15 folder 3
    - Fortner, Max - Offprints
      Text box 12 folder 16
    - Winter, E. - Offprint
      Text box 16 folder 9
    - Fajans, Kazimierz - Offprints (14 items)
      Text box 12 folder 14
    - Antropoff, Andreas von - Offprints
      Text box 11 folder 1
    - Mittasch, Alwin - Offprints
      Text box 14 folder 19
    - Goldschmidt, V.M. - Offprints, (1 of 2)
      Text box 13 folder 5
    - Bredig, Georg - Offprints, no. 98-119 (21 items)
      Text box 11 folder 17
    - Boltwood, B.B. - Offprint
      Text box 11 folder 6
    - Goldschmidt, Stefan - Offprints
      Text box 13 folder 4
    - Spitalsky, Eugen - Offprints
      Text box 16 folder 4
    - Bragg, William Lawrence - Offprint
      Text box 11 folder 9
    - Jaeger, F.M. - Offprints
      Text box 14 folder 3
    - Einstein, Albert - Offprints
      Text box 12 folder 12
    - Jacobsohn, Kurt - Offprint
      Text box 14 folder 2
    - G. Bredig u. Mitarbeiter. I. No. 1-30, Anorganische Fermente
      Books box 17 volume 1
    - Bredig, Georg - Offprints, no. 16-29 (12 items)
      Text box 11 folder 12
    - Disertationen aus G. Bredig's Laboratorium. Band I. A-C.
      Books box 20 volume 1
    - Hedvall, J. Arvid - Offprints
      Text box 13 folder 9
    - G. Bredig u. Mitarbeiter. II. No. 31-60, Katalyse Pt. Katalysen, Pulsationen, Hydroperoxyd.
      Books box 17 volume 2
    - Herlinger, E. - Offprint
      Text box 13 folder 11
    - Millar, W.S. - Offprint
      Text box 14 folder 18
    - Kuhn, Werner - Offprints
      Text box 14 folder 11
    - Sachs, Arthur - Offprint
      Text box 15 folder 5
    - Denham, H.G. - Offprint
      Text box 12 folder 10
    - Bredig, Georg - Offprints, no. 46-65 (23 items)
      Text box 11 folder 14
    - Kuhn, Werner - Offprint, "Georg Bredig - 1868-1944 - In Memoriam"
      Text box 14 folder 12
    - Schlumberger, E. and W. Piotrowski - Offprint
      Text box 15 folder 7
    - Burgeni, A. - Offprints
      Text box 12 folder 7
    - Pastanogoff, W. - Offprint
      Text box 14 folder 21
    - Brossa, G. A. - Offprints
      Text box 12 folder 5
    - Bredig, Georg - Offprints, assorted (18 items)
      Text box 12 folder 3
    - Pauli, Wolfgang - Offprint
      Text box 14 folder 22
    - G. Bredig u. Mitarbeiter. VI-VII. No. 156-202, Physikal. Chemie, Photochemie, Nekrologe, Rektoratsrede, Klassikerausgaben, Patente, etc.
      Books box 19 volume 6
    - Oesper, Ralph E. - Bio-sketch of Georg Bredig from the Journal of Chemical Education
      Text box 14 folder 20
    - Hornburg, Gunther - Offprint
      Text box 13 folder 16
    - Heller, W. - Offprint
      Text box 13 folder 10
    - Disertationen aus G. Bredig's Laboratorium. Band III. J-O.
      Books box 20 volume 3
    - Wolf, K.L. - Offprint
      Text box 16 folder 11
    - Bohm, J. and F. Ganter - Offprints, 1928 - Offprint, 1931
      Text box 11 folder 5
    - Koch, F.K.V. and H. Kohner - Offprint
      Text box 14 folder 7
    - Sieverts, A. - Offprint
      Text box 15 folder 10
    - Shirado, Manjiro - Offprints
      Text box 15 folder 9
    - Hogness, T.R. and E.G. Lunn, - Offprints
      Text box 13 folder 13
    - Bredig, Georg - Offprints, no. 30-43
      Text box 11 folder 13
    - Braune - Offprint
      Text box 11 folder 10
    - Bonhoeffer, K.F. & P. Harteck - Offprint
      Text box 11 folder 7
    - Disertationen aus G. Bredig's Laboratorium. Band II. D-H.
      Books box 20 volume 2
    - Lichty, D.M. - Offprint
      Text box 14 folder 14
    - Wasserman, Albert - Offprints
      Text box 16 folder 7
    - Sommerefeld, A. - Offprint
      Text box 16 folder 2
    - Holmberg, Brother - Offprint
      Text box 13 folder 15
    - Kratky, O. - Offprints
      Text box 14 folder 8
    - Planck, Max - Offprints
      Text box 14 folder 23
    - Haber, Fritz - Offprints
      Text box 13 folder 8
    - Saltpeter, J. - Offprint
      Text box 15 folder 6
    - Jablczynski, Kasimir - Offprint
      Text box 14 folder 1
    - Meisenheimer, Jakob - Offprint
      Text box 14 folder 17
    - Weinmayr, Ignaz - Offprint
      Text box 16 folder 8
  - Series III, Sub-Series II: Books
    These are the scientific works collected and saved from destruction by Georg Bredig. Included among these volumes are books collected by Max Bredig. The books are almost exclusively scientific in nature and have a heavy emphasis on physical chemistry. In some cases, the books are autographed by the author.
    - Auerbach, Friedrich. Die Elemente der Sechsten Gruppe Des Periodischen Systems: Zweite Hälfte/Herausgegeben Von Fr. Auerbach, Leipzig
      Books volume 4
    - Bredig, Georg. Die Elemente der Chemischen Kinetik: Mit Besonderer Berücksichtigung der Katalyse Und der Fermentwirkung. Wiesbaden: J.F. Bergmann
      Books volume 14
    - Ostwald, Wilhelm. Der Werdegang Einer Wissenschaft: 7 Gemeinverständliche Vorträge Aus D. Geschichte D. Chemie. Leipzig: Akad. Verl. -Ges
      Books volume 86
    - Nernst, Walther. Theoretische Chemie Vom Standpunkte der Avogadroschen Regel Und der Thermodynamik.
      Books volume 81
    - Ostwald, Wolfgang. Die Welt der Vernachlässigten Dimensionen: Eine Einführung in Die Moderne Kolloidchemie: Mit Besonderer Berücksichtigung Ihrer Anwendungen. Dresden etc.
      Books volume 88
    - Ruer, Rudolf. Metallographie in Elementarer Darstellung. Leipzig: Voss
      Books volume 198
    - Ostwald, Wolfgang, and Paul Wolski. Kleines Praktikum der Kolloidchemie. Dresden: Steinkopff
      Books volume 91
    - Jaeger, F M. The George Fisher Baker Non-Resident Lectureship in Chemistry at Cornell University: I: Spatial Arrangements of Atomic Systems and Optical Activity: Ii: Methods, Results and Problems of Precise Measurements at High Temperatures: Iii: The Constitution and Structure of Ultramarines. New York, N.Y: McGraw-Hill
      Books volume 60
    - Grube, Georg. Grundzüge Der Theoretische Und Angewandten Elektrochemie. Dresden und Leipzig: Steinkopff
      Books volume 47
    - Magnus, Alfred. Lehrbuch Der Thermodynamik. Leipzig: Akad. Verl. Ges
      Books volume 75
    - Haber, Fritz. Aus Leben Und Beruf; Aufsaetze, Reden, Vortraege. Mit Einem Bildnis. Berlin: J. Springer
      Books volume 53
    - Madigan, Thomas F. A. Biographical Index of American Public Men. New York
      Books volume 74
    - Buchwald, Eberhard. Einführung in Die Kristalloptik. Berlin: Walter de Gruyter
      Books volume 21
    - Fajans, Kasimir, and Joseph Wüst. Physikalisch-chemisches Praktikum. Leipzig: Akad. Verl. Ges
      Books volume 38
    - Bredig, Georg. I. Beiträge Zur Stöchiometrie der Ionenbeweglichkeit: Ii. Uber Die Affinitätsgrössen der Basen: Inaugural-Dissertation Der Hohen Philosophischen Fakultät der Universität Leipzig Zur Erlangung der Doctorwürde. Leipzig: W. Engelmann
      Books volume 11
    - Sauerwald, Franz. Physikalische Chemie der Metallurgischen Reaktionen. Ein Leitfaden der Theoretischen Hüttenkunde. Berlin: s.n.
      Books volume 199
    - G. Bredig: Seinen Freunden Zur Erinnerung. Ko̊then (17 copies)
      Books volume 17
    - Burgess, George K, Chatelier H. Le, Gustav Leithäuser, and George K. Burgess. Die Messung Hoher Temperaturen.
      Books volume 22
    - Bjerrum, Niels. Kurzes Lehrbuch der Anorganischen Chemie. Berlin
      Books volume 10
    - Le, Chatelier H. Lecons Sur Le Carbone: La Combustion, Les Lois Chimiques. Paris: Dunod & Pinat
      Books volume 69
    - Soddy, Frederick. Die Chemie der Radio-Elemente: 2. Leipzig: Barth
      Books volume 205
    - Tammann, Gustav. Lehrbuch Der Metallographie: Chemie U. Physik D. Metalle Und Ihrer Legierungen.
      Books volume 207
    - Roth, Walter and Karl Scheel. Landolt-börnstein Physikalisch-Chemische Tabellen, Dritter Erganzungsband III, Berlin: Verlag von Julius Springer
      Books volume 197
    - Drucker, C, and E Proskauer. Physikalisch-chemisches Taschenbuch Band I. Leipzig: Akad. Verl. -Ges
      Books volume 31
    - Thompson, Silvanus P, and Klaus Clusius. Höhere Mathematik - Und Doch Verständlich: Einf. in D. Differential U. Integralrechnung. Leipzig: Akad. Verl. -Ges
      Books volume 208
    - Günther, Paul. Fritz Haber, Ein Mann der Jahrhundertwende.
      Books volume 48
    - Karrer, Paul. Lehrbuch Der Organischen Chemie: Mit 6 Abb. Im Text U. Auf 1 Taf. Leipzig: G. Thieme
      Books volume 63
    - Soddy, Frederick. Die Chemie der Radio-Elemente: 1. Leipzig: Barth
      Books volume 204
    - Rinne, Friedrich. Die Kristalle Als Vorbilder des Feinbaulichen Wesens der Materie: Mit Einer Zeichnung von A. Dürer, Den Bildnissen von P. V. Groth, M. V. Laue, W.c. V. Röntgen Und A. Schönflies Auf Fünf Kunstdrucktafeln Sowie Mit Hundert Textfiguren. Berlin: Borntraeger
      Books volume 193
    - Zsigmondy, Richard. Kolloidchemie: Ein Lehrbuch. Leipzig: O. Spamer
      Books volume 213
    - Löwe, Fritz. Optische Messungen des Chemikers Und des Mediziners. Dresden und Leipzig
      Books volume 73
    - Wedekind, E. Stereochemie. Berlin und: W. de Gruyter & Co.
      Books volume 212
    - Niggli, Paul. Lehrbuch Der Mineralogie. Berlin: Borntraeger
      Books volume 83
    - Bredig, Georg. Über Die Chemie der Extremen Temperaturen: Habilitationsvorlesung. Leipzig: S. Hirzel
      Books volume 12
    - Skłodowska-Curie, Marie, Walther Kaufmann, and Marie Skłodowska-Curie. Untersuchungen Über Die Radioaktiven Substanzen: Mit Eingedruckten Abb. Braunschweig: Vieweg & Sohn
      Books volume 203
    - Ostwald, Wilhelm. Lebenslinien, Eine Selbstbiographie, T. 1.
      Books volume 92
    - Bredig, Georg. Denkmethoden der Chemie. Leipzig
      Books volume 16
    - Simmons, George H, Morris Fishbein, and George H. Simmons. Anleitung Zur Niederschrift Und Veröffentlichung Medizinischer Arbeiten. Berlin: Springer
      Books volume 201
    - Ostwald, Wilhelm. Prinzipien Der Chemie Eine Einleitung in Alle Chemischen Lehrbücher. Leipzig: Akad. Verlagsges
      Books volume 87
    - Roth, Walther A. Grundzüge der Chemie Für Ingenieure: Mit Besonderer Berücksichtigung der Anorganischen Chemie Und Technologie. Braunschweig: Vieweg
      Books volume 194
    - Meyer, Richard. Michael Faraday, Naturgeschichte Einer Kerze: Sechs Vorlesungen Für Die Jugend. Dresden: Schultze (autographed)
      Books volume 77
    - Niggli, Paul. Geometrische Kristallographie des Diskontinuums: Teil 2.
      Books volume 82
    - Groth, Paul. Elemente Der Physikalischen Und Chemischen Kristallographie; Mit 25 Stereoskopbildern. München: Oldenbourg
      Books volume 46
    - Bernthsen, August. Kurzes Lehrbuch der Organischen Chemie. Braunschweig: Vieweg
      Books volume 8
    - Ephraim, Fritz. Anorganische Chemie. Dresden & Leipzig: Th. Steinkopff
      Books volume 35
    - Jaeger, Francis M. Eine Anleitung Zur Ausführung Exakter Physiko-Chemischer Messungen Bei Höheren Temperaturen: Mit Besonderer Berücksichtigung des Studiums der Mineralsynthese Und der Silikatchemie. Groningen: J.B. Wolters' u.m
      Books volume 61
    - Cohen, Ernst. Uit Het Land van Benjamin Franklin. Zutphen: Thieme
      Books volume 26
    - Ewald, Paul P. Kristalle Und Röntgenstrahlen.
      Books volume 37
    - Ramm, Eberhard. Aus Luft Durch Kohle Zum Stickstoffdünger; Vom Stickstoffdünger Zu Brot Und Reichlicher Nahrung.
      Books volume 192
    - Haber, Fritz, and Arthur B. Lamb. Thermodynamics of Technical Gas-Reactions. Seven Lectures ... Translated by Arthur B. Lamb ... with 20 Figures. Longmans & Co: London
      Books volume 52
    - Hoff, J. H. Lois De L'équilibre Chimique Dans L'état Dilué, Gazeux Ou Dissous. Stockholm: Kongl. Boktryckeriet
      Books volume 54
    - Broglie, Louis. Einführung in Die Wellenmechanik. Akad. Verlagsges: Leipzig
      Books volume 18
    - Bredig, Georg. Katalyse. Berlin
      Books volume 15